

Mahdi Karimian

Date of birth: 11 Mar 1990 | Gender: Male | Email address: mahdii.kariimiian@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

My life has always been associated with creating any kind of contents. I have experienced various careers such as writing, journalism, content creation and podcasting, and I achieved great success in all these jobs in my country.

After immigrating to Europe, I decided to focus on another type of creativity that has a common universal language, that is technology world with the language of programming. In the last few months, I have been diligently learning the fundamentals of front-end. So far I've got a handle on HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and now I'm diving into React and its huge ecosystem.

It's hard to put into words how much I have been under the influence of the indescribable realm of programming. Every day I'm filled with learning the amazing capabilities of this interesting and stunning domain.

DIGITAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React Frame Work | HTML | CSS | Tailwind | JSON | Bootstrap | Git

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PERSIAN**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 - CURRENT Tehran, Iran

PODCAST CREATOR SELF-EMPLOYED

This is a mythology-focused podcast that included humor and detailed information.

- Presented with a friendly and attractive tone
- quickly became one of the most popular podcasts in Iran, with more than 30,000 listeners.

This experience turned my attention to the details that attract the audience's attention. As I transitioned from the podcast to website development, I discovered similarities in connecting with the audience.

Business or Sector Arts, entertainment and recreation | **Department** ostooraakh podcast

2017 - 2020 Tehran, Iran

EDITORIAL DIRECTOR ALLAMEH TABATABAEI HIGH SCHOOL

I worked as the Editorial Director at the Content Production Department, where I had a diverse role such as:

- covering the news and activities and upload on the site.
- designing and implementing various festivals and competitions for students.

This position provided me with valuable insights into managing groups and resolving potential challenges between site designers and users. This experience enriched my perspective as I transitioned into front-end development.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2016 - 2018 Tehran, Iran

STORYTELLING AND CREATIVE WRITING SKILLS Payame Noor University

2019 - 2023 Tehran, Iran

TRANSLATION AND INTERPRETING Payame Noor University

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

2023 - CURRENT

My Github Repositories This is my GitHub profile, where you can find a collection of over 30 small projects primarily sourced from "frontendmentors.io." While these projects are one-page creations, they mirror the challenges encountered in real website development. Feel free to explore my repository to get a glimpse of my skills and passion for creating intuitive and interactive digital experiences.

Link https://github.com/Mahdii-Kariimiian

My Portfolio This is my portfolio showcasing my diverse skills and experiences, complementing the information provided in my CV. I invite you to explore my work to gain a deeper understanding of my capabilities and achievements.

Link https://mahdikarimianportfolio.netlify.app/